#### **Paul Toner**

## Washington, D.C. | Portfolio | Github | (720) 276-1928 | paul@paulyprograms.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

A customer-service professional of 10+ years, I developed teamwork, leadership, and communication skills, and... I know what it's like to be the new guy, from multiple professional experiences. I know the grind it takes to earn the respect of my peers and superiors. This will all be demonstrated in an **entry level software development role** at a company that values career development for its junior engineers.

#### **SKILLS**

Frameworks: React, Next, EJS, Styled-Components, Express, Material UI / Emotion

Languages: Javascript, CSS / SCSS, HTML, Node.js

Database: Mongo DevOps: Git

**Cloud Platforms:** AWS code deployment

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

El Five Restaurant, Denver, CO
Server | January 2020 - June 2022
Demonstrated leadership as a captain and trainer for new employees for 1.5 years

Frasca Food and Wine, Boulder, CO
Server | September 2017 - December 2019
Demonstrated versatility by performing 6 different roles in the front of house
Won the 2019 James Beard Award for Service as part of a 15-person team
Finalist for the 2018 James Beard Award for Best Restaurant as part of a 15-person team

## **EDUCATION**

Howard Community College Columbia, MD, Finance 2011-2013
The Web Developer Bootcamp Udemy Colt Steele August 2022
The Modern React Bootcamp Udemy Colt Steele September 2022
Advanced CSS and SASS Course Udemy Jonas Schmedtmann October 2022

### **PROJECTS**

# sort-spotify.com | Github Repository

January 2023 - Present

Full-stack web site that allows the user to sort through their "Liked Songs" playlist from Spotify and save the results as a new playlist in their account. Spotify does not yet provide this feature, and this website is likely the only in existence that does so.

- 3 monthly users
- 897 lines of React front end
- 285 lines of Express back end
- 1417 lines of custom CSS using the styled-components library / CSS in JS

# paulyprograms.com | Github Repository

January 2023 - Present

Front-end focused showcase that features screen-recorded videos that walk the viewer through the functionality of other notable projects with commentary about the engineering process.

- 864 lines of React
- 1132 lines of custom SASS